Le Nguyen

Full-Stack Software Engineer

ltnguyenswe@gmail.com | New York, NY

Portfolio: ltnguyen517.github.io GitHub: github.com/ltnguyen517 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/le-nguyen-mbs

PROJECTS

Amplify Live | GitHub Repo

(Python / JavaScript / React / Redux / Flask / SQLAlchemy / Postgres / AWS S3 / HTML5 / CSS / Render) Full-Stack Spotify clone where users can create and follow their favorite playlists and stream music.

- Integrated React to develop a highly customizable media player component that allows users to track song
 completion using Redux and handles the next song in the queue, thus enhancing users' personalized music
 listening experience.
- Built a robust search feature using React, allowing users to quickly find and add their favorite tracks to their
 playlists while utilizing AWS S3 to enable seamless playlist image uploads, reducing server load and ensuring
 scalable image services.
- Designed a scalable RESTful API using Flask, allowing for efficient communication between client and server and improving overall application performance.
- Employed modern front-end technologies such as HTML and CSS to create a visually appealing and responsive
 user interface, resulting in a seamless and intuitive user experience while also implementing a secure
 authentication system utilizing bcrypt and JWT to protect user data and privacy.

HomeyBnB Live | GitHub Repo

(JavaScript / React / Redux / Express / Sequelize / PostgresQL / SQLite3 / HTML / CSS / Render)
Full-Stack Airbnb clone where users can search through a vast listing of properties, read reviews, and HomeyBnB their home.

- Skillfully executed the design and styling of the React front-end, seamlessly matching the user interface of Airbnb and providing a user-friendly experience.
- Ensured user privacy and autonomy through frontend and backend authentication measures, allowing users to only access and make changes to their own spots and reviews when logged in.
- Developed RESTful APIs using Express.js to enable smooth data flow between front-end and back-end.
- · Utilized React Hooks and functional components to improve code maintainability, increasing overall efficiency.

LCSX Live | GitHub Repo

(Python / JavaScript / React / Redux / Flask / SQLAlchemy / PostgresQL / HTML / CSS / Render)
Full-Stack Yelp group project with robust user features including reviews and searching for local restaurants.

- Developed and implemented the user profile page using React and Redux, allowing users to manage their account information and view their previous activity.
- Constructed and designed the sign-up and login pages utilizing React and Redux, enabling users to easily create
 and manage their accounts.
- Actively collaborated with a team of three developers, utilizing Agile methodologies, such as SCRUM, and Git for
 efficient version control and teamwork.
- Demonstrated strong adaptability in a fast-paced work environment by participating in daily meetings to identify and resolve project challenges and ensure timely delivery of a one-week project deadline.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Medical Scribe

New York, NY, USA

October 2017 — January 2019

CityMD Urgent Care Walk-in Medical Clinic

- Facilitated efficient patient care by documenting medical history, physical exam findings, and treatments in real-time, resulting in an average of 20% reduction in patient wait times.
- Collaborated with healthcare providers to ensure accurate and complete documentation of patient visits, resulting in improved continuity of care and reduced errors in medical records by 15%.
- Leveraged knowledge of medical terminology and procedures to accurately transcribe patient charts and records, honing my attention to detail and ability to manage complex data.
- Cooperated with healthcare professionals to identify areas of improvement in the electronic medical records system, resulting in a 30% decrease in documentation errors.

VOLUNTEER & RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Secretary and Events Director

June 2011 — Present

Chieu Kien Buddhist Temple

Bronx, NY, USA

- Successfully managed and coordinated various events, including fundraising drives and meditation retreats, that served to raise funds to benefit the welfare of the community.
- Designed and produced email communications using Mailchimp, resulting in a 30% increase in email open rates and engagement with the temple community.
- Facilitated effective communication and collaboration among temple staff and volunteers by leading weekly meetings and maintaining detailed meeting minutes, resulting in improved team dynamics.

Researcher *Geisinger Commonwealth School of Medicine*

August 2016 — May 2017

Scranton, PA, USA

- Collaborated with a team of researchers to design a study aimed at investigating the association between trusting formal or informal sources of health information and smoking cessation, utilizing best practices for data analysis.
- Presented research findings at a research symposium, employing communication skills and data visualization to engage with a diverse audience and answer questions.
- Demonstrated strong attention to detail in data management, ensuring that all study information was properly recorded and accounted for.

SKILLS

Programming & Scripting

- > Javascript
- > Python
- > TypeScript
- ➤ SQL
- ➤ HTML5
- ➤ CSS

Frameworks/Tools

- > React
- Redux
- Express.js
- Node.js
- Flask
- Sequelize
- SQLAlchemy
- ➤ SQLite3
- PostgreSQL
- Amazon Web Services S3 (AWS)
- > jQuery
- ➤ Git
- > Render
- > Firebase

Key Skills

- > Pair Programming
- Test-Driven Development (TDD)
- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Scrum and Agile Development Methodologies
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Custom Auth
- > Empathetic
- Detail Oriented
- Data Analysis and Collection

Languages

- > English
- Vietnamese
- Spanish

EDUCATION

App Academy

Highly selective Full-Stack Web Development bootcamp with a 3% acceptance rate

St. George's University School of Medicine

Strong background in medical diagnostics and treatment strategies

Geisinger Commonwealth School of Medicine

Masters in Biomedical Sciences (M.B.S.) with a 3.62 GPA

Stony Brook University

➤ Bachelor of Science in Interdisciplinary Biology (B.S.)

AWARDS AND HONORS

- Certificate of Medical Humanities from Overlook Medical Center/Atlantic Health
- Alpha Epsilon Lambda Honor Society
- Sigma Beta Honor Society
- National Society of Collegiate Scholars
- Dean's Honors List (5 semesters)